<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Glimpse</title>
    <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Glimpse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 19:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anniversary Plans</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/anniversary-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/anniversary-plans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt; page for social media and news links to follow our progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;revamped-release-schedule&#34;&gt;Revamped release schedule&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We no longer intend to produce an interim Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.4 release, although much of the work for it has been done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original intention behind 0.1.4 was to provide fixes for a show-stopping crash on some Linux distributions quickly, while also including changes Windows users would find useful. However, as re-releasing 0.1.2 on Linux solved the problem that is no longer necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glimpse Image Editor 0.2.0 will be based on the GNU Image Manipulation Program 2.10.18 and use newer versions of BABL, GEGL and MyPaint. We expect to release it in July 2020, which will mean that our third release coincides with this project&amp;rsquo;s first anniversary celebrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to uplifting the base versions, Glimpse Image Editor 0.2.0 will include changes to icon packs, more features in our Windows installer, a Linux AppImage, and an optional Linux AppImage download that contains extra third party plug-ins. You can track our progress in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/milestone/12&#34;&gt;0.2.0 milestone&lt;/a&gt; on Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have also moved a number of feature suggestions into a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/milestone/5&#34;&gt;0.2.x candidate&lt;/a&gt; milestone on Github, and some of these features will be picked up either as part of Glimpse Image Editor 0.2.0 or a future maintenance release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planning-for-the-longer-term&#34;&gt;Planning for the longer term&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been reviewing how our project has been progressing every few months, but now we are approaching the end of our first year we are starting to think about how we can support our application in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that end, we have ended our plans to run our own self-hosted Jenkins and Gitea servers because of the required monetary and time cost of doing so. Instead we will make use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/features/actions&#34;&gt;Github Actions&lt;/a&gt; to automate the building and packaging of our applications. It is a zero-cost solution that is future-proofed and easily portable to other platforms such as Gitlab CI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly we intend to move our wiki to our Github repository instead of running MediaWiki on its own server, and due to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/395&#34;&gt;an outage we experienced&lt;/a&gt; earlier today we have already migrated our website to Github Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that 0.2.0 will include all the initial functionality we promised, so our main costs from now on would be related to collaboration tools. Because we now know roughly how many contributors we need to provide services for and how large our user base is likely to be, we have determined that these services should be sufficient for our project&amp;rsquo;s needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently Bobby Moss is the solo developer of the forked code, with up to a dozen other people providing assistance with packaging, design, testing, moderation and governance. You can use the links on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt; page to follow their progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luna also runs a separate team composed of herself and several designers that are working on a complete UI rewrite. We will provide more details about this in future blog posts, but in the meantime you can follow their progress &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/hZhRceq&#34;&gt;on Discord&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-this-impact-donations&#34;&gt;How does this impact donations?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will continue to accept donations on &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;Open Collective&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sponsors/glimpse-editor&#34;&gt;Github Sponsors&lt;/a&gt;, just as we do now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we are a not-for-profit project and the costs for maintaining the forked code will effectively become $0 USD, we intend to uphold our previous pledge to pass all remaining money after costs to the GNU Image Manipulation Program. This will happen towards the end of July 2020, when we have completed our infrastructure migration, released Glimpse Image Editor 0.2.0 and received our first disbursement from Github Sponsors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From July 2020, all new donations we receive from our backers will be specifically earmarked for producing a new image editing application with a completely different user interface that is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; based on the GNU Image Manipulation Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will clearly communicate that change to our backers so we continue to ensure they make informed choices about how they can best support our project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-future-of-our-fork&#34;&gt;The future of our fork&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://trechnex.freeshell.org/&#34;&gt;Bobby Moss&lt;/a&gt; has indicated that 0.2.0 (based on the GNU Image Manipulation Program 2.10.18) is the last feature release he intends to develop for the &amp;ldquo;fork&amp;rdquo; stream. He will continue to produce 0.2.x maintenance releases periodically to ensure the program is stable and continues to work until the UI rewrite is ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank him for lending us his experience, thousands of unpaid volunteer hours, and the $100 USD donation that helped us get this project started. We would particularly like to thank him for being our contact with the GNU Image Manipulation Program developers, and for the time he spent &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/227#issuecomment-620214794&#34;&gt;trying to port&lt;/a&gt; Glimpse Image Editor to MacOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glimpse Image Editor 0.2.0 will complete the rebranding effort, finish improving the installation experience on Windows, and include a number of minor features and UI fixes that users have requested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;download-figures-update&#34;&gt;Download figures update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All figures were correct on the day this blog post was published and sources have been provided so that you can verify our claims. If the figures are accurate then we would consider this to mean that Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.2 has been positively-received by users. We can confirm that the number of downloads has increased since 2020-03-17. &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/changing-plans/&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that Glimpse Image Editor has been downloaded at least 45608 (+33064) times across all platforms, versions and download sources since it was first released on 2019-11-22. A detailed breakdown is provided below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;linux&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heather Ellsworth reports that there have been 16901 (+15278) active users over the last month that have installed Glimpse Image Editor through Snapcraft. This outlier is likely due to us being a featured application on the Ubuntu Software Center for a a short period in March 2020. &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/glimpse-snap-2020-05-04.png&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glimpse Image Editor has been downloaded 13225 (+7951) times from Flathub across all versions since it was first released on 2019-11-22. &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/ahayzen/flathub-api-stats-generator&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distribution tarballs we provided on Github for Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.2 have been downloaded 356 (+303) times. &lt;a href=&#34;https://somsubhra.com/github-release-stats/?username=glimpse-editor&amp;amp;repository=Glimpse&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not have the figures for other community-supported Linux download sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;windows&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.2 has been downloaded 9920 (+4650) times from Github since its release on 2020-03-02. &lt;a href=&#34;https://somsubhra.com/github-release-stats/?username=glimpse-editor&amp;amp;repository=Glimpse&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To date there have been 5021 (+70) direct downloads of Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.0 for Windows from Github since its release on 2019-11-22. &lt;a href=&#34;https://somsubhra.com/github-release-stats/?username=glimpse-editor&amp;amp;repository=Glimpse&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two new unofficial third-party download sources for Windows users that provide download statistics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;97 (+25) downloads from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.softpedia.com/dyn-search.php?search_term=glimpse&#34;&gt;Softpedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;88 (+59) downloads from &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/projects/glimpse-image-editor/&#34;&gt;SourceForge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Month of Many Patches</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/a-month-of-many-patches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/a-month-of-many-patches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt; page for social media and news links to follow our progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;updated-timelines-for-glimpse-image-editor-014&#34;&gt;Updated timelines for Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We plan to release Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.4 beta before the end of April 2020. That may be delayed if it takes longer than anticipated to resolve Windows build problems, or if we are badly impacted by the current global health emergency. There will then be two weeks of testing before it is formally released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To recap, we are bumping the versions for key underlying dependencies on the same GNU Image Manipulation Program 2.10.12 base. We have already backported &amp;ldquo;high contrast&amp;rdquo; icon packs, and have started improving the ones that are already there. We also want to use the extra time to improve translations and documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have had positive feedback about our existing Windows MSI installer only using ~500MB disk space (the upstream Windows installer uses 3.5GB). For 0.1.4 we will refine it further with a prototype GUI that displays the GNU GPLv3 and enables users to set a custom install location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a few weeks of releasing Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.4, we will produce AppImages for Linux users. They will contain an in-built update mechanism, and function as &amp;ldquo;known good&amp;rdquo; builds for anyone that has trouble installing Flatpaks and Snaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also want to produce a new install option for Windows 10 users through the Microsoft Store as soon as possible. We believe that will resolve issues installing and running Glimpse Image Editor on enterprise computers. Typically anti-virus programs on those machines will incorrectly flag the software as malware and/or interfere with its normal operation, but hopefully a sandboxed version of the program that has been security audited and signed by Microsoft will not have those problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June 2020 we intend to start porting 0.1.4 to macOS, with the aim of releasing a beta version in time for our project&amp;rsquo;s first anniversary in July 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;glimpse-image-editor-featured-in-the-ubuntu-software-center&#34;&gt;Glimpse Image Editor featured in the Ubuntu Software Center&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, Glimpse Image Editor was recently displayed up in a huge banner at the top of the Ubuntu Software Center. We now also appear in the &amp;ldquo;Graphics &amp;amp; Photography&amp;rdquo; section too! Both of these things significantly boosted the size of our user base on Linux, and we now treat Flathub and Snapcraft as equally supported download channels for that operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank Heather Ellsworth and Ken VanDine for their amazing work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://snapcraft.io/glimpse-editor&#34;&gt;our Snapcraft builds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;glimpse-image-editor-012-re-released-with-important-linux-fixes&#34;&gt;Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.2 re-released with important Linux fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of March 2020 we discovered that upgrading the GNOME platform version on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flathub.org/apps/details/org.glimpse_editor.Glimpse&#34;&gt;our Flatpak&lt;/a&gt; from 3.34 to 3.36 broke our application and prevented it from launching. We initially thought that problem was specific to Flathub and that reverting back to 3.34 was sufficient, but on further investigation discovered that this problem still impacted Arch and Elementary users running GNOME 3.36.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within days Bobby Moss successfully backported a patch from upstream that fixed this showstopping bug. Cristiano Vitorino then provided his assistance with the testing of that fix over the next week, enabling Bobby to deploy the change through Flathub on 2020-04-03.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Glimpse Project governance team would like to express their gratitude to the Arch Linux community for originally reporting this problem to us, and for quickly updating the AUR package they provide for Glimpse Image Editor with this fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-github-sponsors-donation-option&#34;&gt;New Github Sponsors donation option&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, your Open Collective pledges will still continue as normal. We are just making you aware that this is another donation option that we are starting to share with the community. All the donations we receive on Github Sponsors will go directly to our existing Open Collective campaign that covers project costs, but with the added benefit that Github will match your contribution for the first year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glimpse project Github Sponsors link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sponsors/glimpse-editor&#34;&gt;https://github.com/sponsors/glimpse-editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glimpse project Open Collective link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;https://opencollective.com/glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GNU Image Manipulation Program donation link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/donating/&#34;&gt;https://www.gimp.org/donating/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://trechnex.freeshell.org/&#34;&gt;Bobby Moss&lt;/a&gt;, our creator and main developer, has also started a personal Github Sponsors account. If you would like to thank him for the 1000+ unpaid hours he&amp;rsquo;s spent working on this not-for-profit project so far, you can do so via this link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sponsors/TrechNex&#34;&gt;https://github.com/sponsors/TrechNex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;assistance-provided-to-the-gnu-image-manipulation-program&#34;&gt;Assistance provided to the GNU Image Manipulation Program&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that on 2020-04-01 we donated $100 USD to the GNU Image Manipulation Program developers as part of our commitment to share the donations we receive with them. In total we have donated $150 USD since our project started, and we expect that amount to keep growing in coming months and years. &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse/expenses/categories/DONATION&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would also like to take this opportunity to apologize to the GNU Image Manipulation Program contributors for a separate issue that they reported to us on 2020-04-04.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was previously stated on our FAQs page that their GUI design team had stopped meeting in 2012. While that is correct, it was unfortunately misinterpreted by some bloggers and YouTubers to mean that development on the GNU Image Manipulation Program&amp;rsquo;s user interface had ceased in 2012. We &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/glimpse_editor/status/1246837680735948802&#34;&gt;issued a clarification&lt;/a&gt; on social media, rewrote our FAQs page, then invited upstream contributors to review our changes to that page before we published them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We take our commitment to build a positive and constructive relationship with the GNU Image Manipulation Program contributors very seriously, and we hope our fast response to this incident demonstrates our desire to act in the best interests of the free software community and do the right things as a downstream fork.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Plans</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/changing-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/changing-plans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt; page for social media and news links to follow our progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;glimpse-image-editor-updated-on-snapcraft&#34;&gt;Glimpse Image Editor updated on Snapcraft&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that the Snapcraft version of Glimpse Image Editor was updated to 0.1.2 on 2019-03-12. The feedback we have received about this so far has been very positive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss also worked with Heather Ellsworth to ensure that the “edge” and “beta” channels used by this community-supported download source builds from the correct Github branches, and that the app store text matches what we use for Flathub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find out more here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://snapcraft.io/glimpse-editor&#34;&gt;https://snapcraft.io/glimpse-editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adapting-to-the-coronavirus-covid-19-pandemic&#34;&gt;Adapting to the Coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to reassure our end users, followers and supporters that we take this public health crisis very seriously. The project is taking action to ensure that development continues for as long as possible, and that you are not left without feature improvements and security updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have advised our contributors to avoid attending any free software or Linux conferences on our behalf, and our planned releases over the next six months have also been changed to account for more intermittent contributions from our existing project members. This blog post goes into more detail about that in the &amp;ldquo;Updated release schedule and priorities&amp;rdquo; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we would like to ask all our users to be patient with us over the coming months if there is a delayed response to bug tickets, feature requests, merge approvals, and questions on social media. Our contributors and their families are just as susceptible to COVID-19 as you are, but we will do our best to assist you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out how to help our project progress: &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/contribute/&#34;&gt;https://glimpse-editor.org/contribute/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bolster our funding reserves on Open Collective: &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;https://opencollective.com/glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help the GNU Image Manipulation Program too: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/donating/&#34;&gt;https://www.gimp.org/donating/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;updated-release-schedule-and-priorities&#34;&gt;Updated release schedule and priorities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have decided to create a 0.1.4 release and continue working on the same GNU Image Manipulation 2.10.12 base for the time being instead of creating a new 0.2.0 release based on 2.10.18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for that decision is we want to spend more time fixing bugs and packaging our software for a wider audience. We also expect to have reduced capacity for changes over the next six months, so completely re-basing our hard fork will likely prevent us from working on more meaningful changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, you will not miss out on upstream fixes and improvements. We intend to package Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.4 with new versions of GEGL, BABL and other libraries. Also useful features such as the new high contrast themes and update checker will be backported. We also still plan to pre-bundle useful plugins such as G&amp;rsquo;MIC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will focus on new release packaging first, and aim to release Linux AppImages for 0.1.2 before the end of March 2020, and an MSIX file for those using Windows 10 on their workplace machines in April 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other big changes coming for Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.4 are that we intend to fix the man pages (finally!) and refactor libgimp so that distribution maintainers can package our software without having to mark the GNU Image Manipulation Program as a conflict in their repositories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaomodus will also be working on Jenkins build infrastructure. They will also be evaluating how we can better manage and improve our non-English translations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aim to release Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.4 in May 2020, but that is subject to change based on how well we progress. After 0.1.4 is released we will immediately start work on the macOS port, but if we have spare capacity we will begin work on it sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see a provisional list of all the planned features and fixes here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/milestone/12&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/milestone/12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;download-figures-update&#34;&gt;Download figures update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All figures were correct on the day this blog post was published and sources have been provided so that you can verify our claims. If the figures are accurate then we would consider this to be a good start for our project, and can confirm that the number of downloads has ramped up significantly since 2020-01-31. &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/progress-on-our-first-errata-release/&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that Glimpse Image Editor has been downloaded at least 12544 (+5684) times across all platforms and download sources since it was first released on 2019-11-22. A detailed breakdown is provided below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;linux&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glimpse Image Editor has been downloaded 5274 (+1084) times from Flathub since it was first released. &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/ahayzen/flathub-api-stats-generator&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heather Ellsworth reports that there are 1623 (-7) active users that have installed Glimpse Image Editor through Snapcraft. &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/glimpse-snap-2020-03-14.png&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distribution tarballs we provided on Github for Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.2 have been downloaded 53 times, suggesting that there is some early interest from Linux distro maintainers about hosting our software natively in their repositories. &lt;a href=&#34;https://somsubhra.com/github-release-stats/?username=glimpse-editor&amp;amp;repository=Glimpse&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not have the figures for other community-supported Linux download sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;windows&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.2 installer has been downloaded 552 times from Github since its release on 2020-03-02. &lt;a href=&#34;https://somsubhra.com/github-release-stats/?username=glimpse-editor&amp;amp;repository=Glimpse&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To date there have been 4951 (+761) direct downloads of Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.0 for Windows from Github. &lt;a href=&#34;https://somsubhra.com/github-release-stats/?username=glimpse-editor&amp;amp;repository=Glimpse&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two new unofficial third-party download sources for Windows users that provide download statistics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;62 downloads from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.softpedia.com/dyn-search.php?search_term=glimpse&#34;&gt;Softpedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;29 downloads from &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/projects/glimpse-image-editor/&#34;&gt;SourceForge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glimpse 0.1.2 Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/glimpse-0-1-2-release-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/glimpse-0-1-2-release-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This release iterates on our very first &amp;ldquo;minimal viable product&amp;rdquo; release. The primary objective was to improve the experience for Windows users and fix non-English translation files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also the first release where we have provided a source tarball for Linux distribution packagers. Please note that you will need to mark &lt;code&gt;libgimp&lt;/code&gt; as a conflicting package as there is a lot of code and file name refactoring we still need to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also took community feedback on board and reinstated the &amp;ldquo;Color&amp;rdquo; icon pack and &amp;ldquo;Grey&amp;rdquo; UI theme. Upstream contributors are also now credited in &lt;strong&gt;Help&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;About&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Credits&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GNU/Linux users can install Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.2 as a Flatpak from the Flathub repository. There are also a number of additional installation options for Linux detailed on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/downloads/&#34;&gt;Downloads&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows users can use an MSI file to install Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.2 on 32-bit and 64-bit systems running Windows 7 or later. We chose that type of installer to assist businesses and schools using centralised software management systems. This can also be found on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/downloads/&#34;&gt;Downloads&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;known-issues&#34;&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux AppImages for 0.1.0 and 0.1.2 are not yet available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/108&#34;&gt;#108&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows users cannot run Python plug-ins &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/178&#34;&gt;#178&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no macOS port at the current time &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/227&#34;&gt;#227&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Man pages in the terminal have not been updated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compatibility with upstream offline help pages has not been tested&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-features&#34;&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glimpse 0.1.2 is still based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/news/2019/06/12/gimp-2-10-12-released/&#34;&gt;GNU Image Manipulation Program 2.10.12&lt;/a&gt;. It also still uses the following dependency package versions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gegl.org/babl/&#34;&gt;BABL&lt;/a&gt; 0.1.68&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gegl.org/&#34;&gt;GEGL&lt;/a&gt; 0.4.16&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mypaint.org/&#34;&gt;MyPaint&lt;/a&gt; 1.3.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;windows-improvements&#34;&gt;Windows Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translation files are now included in the MSI installer &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/240&#34;&gt;#240&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glimpse Image Editor and GNU Image Manipulation Program no longer share the same task bar icon &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/247&#34;&gt;#247&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows installer now supports upgrading existing installations &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/314&#34;&gt;#314&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ui-improvements&#34;&gt;UI Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Color&amp;rdquo; icon pack and &amp;ldquo;Gray&amp;rdquo; UI theme have been reinstated &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/232&#34;&gt;#232&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo; brushes have now been removed &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/286&#34;&gt;#286&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upstream contributors and translators are now appropriately credited through the UI &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/228&#34;&gt;#228&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renamed the &amp;ldquo;Gimpressionist&amp;rdquo; plug-in to &amp;ldquo;Impressionist&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/267&#34;&gt;#267&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed various problems in translation files &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/230&#34;&gt;#230&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/238&#34;&gt;#238&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed text color chooser that still used Wilber icon and upstream name &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/250&#34;&gt;#250&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed &amp;ldquo;legacy&amp;rdquo; UI theme in Snapcraft &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/271&#34;&gt;#271&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-improvements&#34;&gt;Code Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moved &lt;code&gt;build&lt;/code&gt; folder to &lt;code&gt;build-aux&lt;/code&gt; to follow GNOME conventions &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/233&#34;&gt;#233&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added packaging documentation to the &lt;code&gt;snap&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;flatpak&lt;/code&gt; folders to match &lt;code&gt;windows-msi&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/305&#34;&gt;#305&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed &lt;code&gt;make check&lt;/code&gt; so we can produce source tarballs for Linux distribution maintainers &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/251&#34;&gt;#251&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank everyone who contributed towards making Glimpse 0.1.2 a success, particularly those unnamed individuals who spread the word about our project on social media, shared their feature requests with us and provided feedback to the development team during the beta testing phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;creator&#34;&gt;Creator&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bobby Moss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;maintainers&#34;&gt;Maintainers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chaomodus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christopher Davis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-contributors&#34;&gt;Code Contributors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heather Ellsworth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ken VanDine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mathieu Bridon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mike Burns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;skyejonke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;documentation-contributors&#34;&gt;Documentation Contributors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dave Kretz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;artwork-contributors&#34;&gt;Artwork Contributors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Daniel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;20-tier-sponsor-contributors&#34;&gt;$20+ Tier Sponsor Contributors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sami Mannila&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-tier-backers-and-one-off-donors&#34;&gt;$5+ Tier Backers and One-off Donors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to say a special thank you to all of our financial backers on &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;Open Collective&lt;/a&gt; regardless of whether they are listed below or not. Without your help this release would not have been possible, and your continued support is highly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chris&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dzuk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Janne Marko&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jes Wolfe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kretz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magnus Gustafsson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nitrohorse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Samuel Pickard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stan Sorochan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tim Dehring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transmutable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Glimpse 0.1.2 Beta</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/announcing-glimpse-0-1-2-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/announcing-glimpse-0-1-2-beta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt; page for social media and news links to follow our progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wait-what-happened-to-011&#34;&gt;Wait&amp;hellip; what happened to 0.1.1?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t panic! We inherited a build versioning scheme that seems to work well, so we now define odd number versions (eg. 0.1.1 and 0.1.99) as &amp;ldquo;in development&amp;rdquo; and even-number versions (eg. 0.1.0 and 0.1.2) as stable releases we take the time to beta test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about how our release numbering works on &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/about/#how-does-your-release-numbering-work&#34;&gt;our FAQs page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beta-testing-for-the-next-release-begins&#34;&gt;Beta testing for the next release begins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday evening Bobby Moss (trechnex) successfully packaged the beta builds for Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.2 and published them on Flathub (Linux) and our own build server (Windows). We would like to also thank Mathieu Bridon for his assistance setting up our project&amp;rsquo;s beta channel on Flathub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have already started two weeks of beta testing and bug fixing. Our target release date for 0.1.2 is Monday 2nd March 2020, but that is subject to change based on the severity of the bugs we uncover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who would like to help us with beta testing, here is a summary of the user-facing changes we have made:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features and fixes ready for testing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Color&amp;rdquo; icon theme added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gray&amp;rdquo; UI theme added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent upstream contributors credited in Help &amp;gt; About &amp;gt; Credits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gimpressionist&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; renamed to &amp;ldquo;Impressionist&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; in Filters &amp;gt; Artistic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows users can now select other languages in Edit &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GNU Image Manipulation Program and Glimpse Image Editor no longer share the same Windows taskbar icon when they run at the same time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features and fixes still being worked on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python-fu support on Windows &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/178&#34;&gt;#178&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upstream translator credits need fixing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/300&#34;&gt;#300&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Windows installer &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/284&#34;&gt;#284&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miscellaneous bugs in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/milestone/9&#34;&gt;0.1.2 milestone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We strongly recommend that you do not attempt to try out these beta testing changes on a production machine you urgently rely on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full instructions for participating in the beta are available on our development wiki: &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Testing_Glimpse&#34;&gt;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Testing_Glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;successful-website-migration&#34;&gt;Successful website migration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago Chaomodus migrated our static hugo site and the development wiki to new servers, and so far we have had no outages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We previously ran everything from one server that Bobby Moss had provisioned in haste last August, so breaking out our systems into several more robust servers is something that promises to help us automate builds and improve uptime for our collaboration tools and websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the next few months we intend to fully decommission the old server and run automated packaging and builds for Linux, Windows and (eventually) macOS on a separate Jenkins slave running Docker containers. Once that work is complete we will be able to spend more time improving Glimpse Image Editor and less on manually building and packaging things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss has already set up a new branching strategy to cover that, and added that information to &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Building_Glimpse&#34;&gt;our development wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;updates-to-our-faqs-page&#34;&gt;Updates to our FAQs page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governance team reviewed and updated a number of questions on our FAQs page, which we felt was important as our project has evolved a lot since some of these answers were written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss also wrote new answers explaining &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/about/#when-are-you-going-to-implement-the-feature-i-asked-for&#34;&gt;how to find out if we&amp;rsquo;re implementing a feature&lt;/a&gt; and an explanation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/about/#how-does-your-release-numbering-work&#34;&gt;how our version numbers work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have additional questions, please contact us by using the links on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-applied-to-join-the-github-sponsors-waiting-list&#34;&gt;We applied to join the Github Sponsors waiting list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After one of our supporters notified us that &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.opencollective.com/double-the-love/&#34;&gt;Github Sponsors now supports Open Collective&lt;/a&gt; we opened up a discussion about it on our public Matrix channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason this development piqued our interest is that all donations submitted via Github Sponsors would go directly to &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;our Open Collective profile&lt;/a&gt; without requiring our intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Github also charges no fees for this service, and they have committed to matching any donations we receive in our first year, up to a limit of $5000 USD. This move would also address the feedback we have received that we should support a secondary donation mechanism for those who do not wish to use PayPal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The response on Matrix was broadly positive, so we have applied to join the waiting list for this platform. Assuming we are accepted, we will briefly re-open the issue so that people can let us know how they feel about this decision before we proceed with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a reminder, money donated to our Open Collective is &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/about/#why-do-you-need-monetary-donations&#34;&gt;only used to cover the costs of this project&lt;/a&gt; and periodically pass some of those contributions upstream. You can see a full accounting of all the donations we have ever received and how we have spent that money so far on &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;our Open Collective profile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to thank our contributors directly for the many hours of unpaid volunteer work they do for our project, you should contact them about their own personal donation platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creator: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TrechNex&#34;&gt;Bobby Moss&lt;/a&gt;
Maintainers: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chaomodus&#34;&gt;Chaomodus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/BrainBlasted&#34;&gt;Christopher Davis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Member1221&#34;&gt;Luna&lt;/a&gt;
Flatpak: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bochecha&#34;&gt;Mathieu Bridon&lt;/a&gt;
Snapcraft: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hellsworth&#34;&gt;Heather Ellsworth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress On Our First Errata Release</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/progress-on-our-first-errata-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/progress-on-our-first-errata-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt; page for social media and news links to follow our progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note:&lt;/strong&gt; We have now moved to a different Mastodon account! Follow us at &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.art/@glimpse&#34;&gt;@glimpse@mastodon.art&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;audience-figures-update&#34;&gt;Audience Figures Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.0 was released on Friday 22nd November 2019. &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/glimpse-0-1-0-release-notes/&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These download figures were correct at the time of publication. There has been 6860 downloads in total from our directly supported sources (Github and Flathub):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our Windows release has been downloaded 4190 times (+490). &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.somsubhra.com/github-release-stats/?username=glimpse-editor&amp;amp;repository=Glimpse&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our Linux release on Flathub has been downloaded 2670 times (+570). &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/ahayzen/flathub-api-stats-generator&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heather Ellsworth reports that there are 1630 active installs from Snapcraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;progress-on-glimpse-image-editor-011&#34;&gt;Progress on Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss created a huge utility pull request that resolved a number of important bugs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GNU Image Manipulation Program and Glimpse Image Editor currently share the same Windows task bar icon if you run them at the same time &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/247&#34;&gt;#247&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still displays &amp;ldquo;GIMP&amp;rdquo; in the splash screen title &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/230&#34;&gt;#230&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;GIMP&amp;rdquo; is still used throughout the Help and About menus in the German translation &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/238&#34;&gt;#238&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;GIMP&amp;rdquo; still being incorrectly used throughout parts of the application in non-English translations &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/240&#34;&gt;#240&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pull request also updated the application version, updated the list of Glimpse contributors, and updated the documentation. You can review all the changes here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/263&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/263&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remaining bugs that still need to be resolved are listed here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;GIMP&amp;rdquo; and Wilber mascot still used in the color picker &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/250&#34;&gt;#250&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restore the &amp;ldquo;Color&amp;rdquo; icon theme &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/232&#34;&gt;#232&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Python Support on Windows &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/178&#34;&gt;#178&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rename the &amp;ldquo;Gimpressionist&amp;rdquo; plug-in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/267&#34;&gt;#267&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have revised our expected release timeline to &amp;ldquo;some time in February 2020&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=User:TrechNex&#34;&gt;Bobby&amp;rsquo;s wiki page&lt;/a&gt; has been updated accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly before this post was published we also received an excellent contribution from Ken VanDine that fixed the legacy user interface theme for Linux users who installed Glimpse Image Editor through Snapcraft. That fix will be included in this release: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/271&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/271&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;updated-plans-for-glimpse-image-editor-020&#34;&gt;Updated Plans for Glimpse Image Editor 0.2.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a number of people (including chaomodus) suggested it, we are now determining how to include &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmic.eu/&#34;&gt;the G&amp;rsquo;MIC toolkit&lt;/a&gt; with Glimpse Image Editor by default. We &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/gmic_ip/status/1217899762554408960&#34;&gt;confirmed with the project&lt;/a&gt; that the license was compatible, and in future releases we will integrate the plug-ins functions more tightly within the user interface. You can follow the Github issue&amp;rsquo;s progress here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/262&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/262&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kretz also suggested that we include the &amp;ldquo;GIMP Resynthesizer&amp;rdquo; plug-in: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/270&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/270&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us know if you have more ideas for plug-ins we should consider bundling with Glimpse Image Editor. You can also see a preview of potential issues we might cover on our milestones page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/milestones&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/milestones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chaomodus-joins-the-glimpse-project-governance-team&#34;&gt;Chaomodus joins the Glimpse project governance team&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have seen chaomodus mentioned in previous blog posts because of their excellent work running &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org&#34;&gt;our development wiki&lt;/a&gt;. They have helped out with the project from the very beginning, and assisted Luna (Clipsey) numerous times with our parallel user interface rewriting efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaomodus has also taken on the task of revamping our build tooling and infrastructure, and recently started trialling a Gitea server as an optional alternative for people who have moral objections to using Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope you will give them a warm welcome as our newest member of the governance team. You can see more details about how the Glimpse project governs itself on &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/about/#how-does-this-project-govern-itself&#34;&gt;our FAQs page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has also not escaped our notice that this continues our trend of diverse representation in leadership positions for our project! The lesson other free software projects can take from us is that if you treat joining your public communication channels as a privilege instead of a right, pro-actively police your project&amp;rsquo;s code of conduct and value creating a pleasant culture over nursing peoples&amp;rsquo; egos, then this can in fact emerge organically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy-yourselves-at-fosdem&#34;&gt;Enjoy yourselves at FOSDEM!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would just like to confirm that we do not have any official representation this year, and none of our governance team are in attendance. We are unlikely to be present at any conferences this year because it is still quite early in our project&amp;rsquo;s lifespan and we do not yet have the resources to send people to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we know many of you are attending FOSDEM this weekend and hope you all have a lovely weekend. The creator of our fork Bobby Moss (who once lived in Belgium for a year and attended FOSDEM himself in 2012 and 2015) particularly recommends &lt;a href=&#34;https://hoegaarden.com/&#34;&gt;Hoegaarden&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://leffe.com/en/leffe-blond&#34;&gt;Leffe Blond&lt;/a&gt; as good beer choices!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kicking Off a New Year</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/kicking-off-a-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 21:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/kicking-off-a-new-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt; page for social media and news links to follow our progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note:&lt;/strong&gt; We have now moved to a different Mastodon account! Follow us at &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.art/@glimpse&#34;&gt;@glimpse@mastodon.art&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;download-figures-update&#34;&gt;Download Figures Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.0 was released on Friday 22nd November 2019. The feedback we have had from end users has been mostly positive, and we are actively working on the translation bugs that have been reported to us. &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/glimpse-0-1-0-release-notes/&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These download figures were correct at the time of publication. We estimated there has been around 7600 downloads so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our Windows release has been downloaded 3700 times. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.somsubhra.com/github-release-stats/?username=glimpse-editor&amp;amp;repository=Glimpse&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our Linux release on Flathub has been downloaded 2100 times. &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/ahayzen/flathub-api-stats-generator&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heather Ellsworth also reports that our Linux release has also been downloaded 1800 times on Snapcraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given this was our very first binary release and most of the coverage our project has received on community blog posts and in YouTube videos has been generally negative, we feel that these figures are as good as we could have hoped for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;updates-from-the-festive-break&#34;&gt;Updates From the Festive Break&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were definitely not idle throughout December 2019! A major discussion currently ongoing is how we will scale our server infrastructure in a &amp;ldquo;long term sustainable&amp;rdquo; way. This year we plan to create automated reproducible builds and packaging for Windows, macOS, Linux Flatpak and Linux AppImage. We will need to provision a build server capable of achieving that, and a separate web server to host our website and published development builds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions have also been re-opened about possibly moving our source code and issue tracking from Github to a more ethical alternative. Chaomodus and meltheadorable are currently working on a proof of concept self-hosted &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitea.io/en-us/&#34;&gt;Gitea&lt;/a&gt; server, and if that proves to be a viable alternative that our community supports we could switch to it. If we do choose to make the switch, we would likely continue mirroring code to Github and using the service as a download mirror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss has been tracking some of the GNU Image Manipulation Program&amp;rsquo;s project IRC channels and mailing lists to help us keep track of upstream bugs and changes that might impact our project. He has also laid out a &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=User:TrechNex&#34;&gt;roadmap of changes&lt;/a&gt; that he intends to contribute to the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luna (Clipsey) has continued to work on the user interface rewrite with the help of other project contributors. She is currently experimenting with cross-platform development frameworks and assessing the viability of our project developing its own user interface toolkit. Our choice of programming language is still an open discussion, and design work for a potential new user interface has started in earnest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we collectively started a discussion about creating an &amp;ldquo;unstable&amp;rdquo; branch as a technical exercise. This would copy the latest changes from our own development branch, but then apply them to the upstream &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branches for GNU Image Manipulation Program, GEGL, BABL and MyPaint. It would not be the version of the code we ever use for stable releases (which always rely on upstream tags) or recommend that anyone use it for productive work, but contributors may find it useful to understand which features we need make fixes for. We will keep you updated on how that discussion progresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bug-fix-release-planned&#34;&gt;Bug-fix Release Planned&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are hoping to release Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.1 either towards of the end of January 2020 or in the first half of February 2020 depending on how we progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anticipated features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restoring the &amp;ldquo;Color&amp;rdquo; icon theme to assist users with high DPI displays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixing translations for the rebrand that still need changes to be applied&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restoring Python support for the Windows version of Glimpse Image Editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will continue to be based on the GNU Image Manipulation Program 2.10.12 so that we can apply and release these changes as quickly as possible for our new user base. There may also be other features that are bundled as part of the update, and we will do our best to keep you up-to-date as our plans evolve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rebase-to-21014-planned&#34;&gt;Rebase to 2.10.14 Planned&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once 0.1.1 has been released we intend to rebase Glimpse Image Editor on GNU Image Manipulation Program 2.10.14 and release the result as version 0.2.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will also be the release where we credit upstream contributions through the graphical user interface. We think this is the best release to add that change in because we will benefit from upstream improvements that also add contributions from translators. To comply with the GNU GPLv3 we include the names of the original authors with the source code, but we want to ensure that they are also credited through the user interface before publishing Glimpse Image Editor to any new download channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We anticipate that Glimpse Image Editor 0.2.0 will be released in early March 2020. Shortly after we will focus on porting the code base to macOS based on the new information we have been provided with by the GNU Image Manipulation Program contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These plans are subject to change, and we may also include new &amp;ldquo;drive-by contributions&amp;rdquo; that have not been mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thank-you&#34;&gt;Thank you&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to take this opportunity to thank everyone that stuck with us through the four months our project was vaporware, and particularly those of you who continue to donate your time, money and ideas to our project today. It means a lot to all of us that work on Glimpse Image Editor, and we are doing our best to push this project to the next level and keep developing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our aim is still to try out new ideas and bring new people into the world of free software. It&amp;rsquo;s still possible that we could fail to achieve broad appeal, and there are many people in the free software community that we will probably never win over, but we are committed to deliver on our promises as best we can and hope we can continue to make our community proud to support us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Successful First Binary Release</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/successful-first-binary-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/successful-first-binary-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday 22nd November 2019 we were pleased to announce our first binary release, Glimpse Image Editor 0.1.0. You can try it out for yourself on &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/downloads/&#34;&gt;our downloads page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also pleased to announced that on Friday 29th November 2019 we released a new &amp;ldquo;signed&amp;rdquo; installer for the Windows platform. The previous &amp;ldquo;unsigned&amp;rdquo; version is still provided for troubleshooting purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop here though. In the New Year we will begin work on bug-fix releases to address translation problems and start working on 0.2.0. You can see a provisional roadmap with candidate issues &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/milestones/&#34;&gt;in these milestones&lt;/a&gt;, but these are subject to change based on discussions in &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.to/#/#glimpse:matrix.org&#34;&gt;our Matrix channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;download-statistics&#34;&gt;Download Statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the day we published this blog post there had been 3641 downloads from our own directly-supported channels. (We do not currently have figures for community-supported channels like Snapcraft and AUR, so this is likely an underestimate for the total number of downloads).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;breakdown-by-platform-and-channel&#34;&gt;Breakdown by platform and channel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unsigned Windows installer: 2037&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signed Windows installer: 387&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.somsubhra.com/github-release-stats/?username=glimpse-editor&amp;amp;repository=Glimpse&#34;&gt;http://www.somsubhra.com/github-release-stats/?username=glimpse-editor&amp;amp;repository=Glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux Flatpak: 1217&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/ahayzen/flathub-api-stats-generator&#34;&gt;https://gitlab.com/ahayzen/flathub-api-stats-generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank everyone that has tried out this release so far, and particularly those who have raised bugs and made feature suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-closed-our-patreon-account&#34;&gt;We closed our Patreon account&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we have mentioned in previous blog posts, we went ahead with our planned decision to close down our Patreon donation account on Friday 6th December 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now only accept donations to the project through &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;Open Collective&lt;/a&gt;. That means we will now miss out on the donations we were receiving from Patreon (effectively halving the amount we receive each month), but we think the loss of revenue is outweighed by the advantages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;benefits-from-our-perspective&#34;&gt;Benefits from our perspective&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fewer costs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easier management of backer rewards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More than one person can administrate our fundraising campaign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;benefits-for-our-donors&#34;&gt;Benefits for our donors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s now the option to donate with a one-off payment &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; a monthly subscription&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US citizens can record contributions as a charitable donation for tax purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to review how we spend backer money helps potential donors make an informed decision before contributing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;benefits-for-the-wider-community&#34;&gt;Benefits for the wider community&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can scrutinize how much money the project receives and from whom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can view itemized spending records and which individuals are paying for things on our behalf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can have confidence that an established 501c charity based in the United States with a proven track record is reviewing our expense claims and raised invoices before they are paid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;patreon-cash-transfers&#34;&gt;Patreon cash transfers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the money we received through Patreon has been transferred to Open Collective over the past few months, and those transactions are listed under an &amp;ldquo;Incognito&amp;rdquo; user that is currently recorded as the top backer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project&amp;rsquo;s founder has also donated $100 over the last six months to cover the various fees and costs associated with those transfers, and ensured that our spending records on Open Collective cover every transaction since the project started on Friday 5th July 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thank-you-to-everyone-who-has-donated-so-far&#34;&gt;Thank you to everyone who has donated so far&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe we have gone above and beyond the usual level of transparency and scrutiny that most free software projects are willing to subject themselves to. We have chosen to do that to ensure governance team can be held accountable for its decisions by the Glimpse project, and to ensure our community can have confidence in our motives and intentions. If you have any concerns, then you are welcome to raise them with us on &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.to/#/#glimpse:matrix.org&#34;&gt;our Matrix channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, as usual, we encourage people to also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/donating/&#34;&gt;donate to the upstream project&lt;/a&gt; to support the excellent work we rely on to make Glimpse Image Editor happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glimpse 0.1.0 Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/glimpse-0-1-0-release-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/glimpse-0-1-0-release-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the very first binary release for Glimpse Image Editor. The primary objective was to complete the re-brand, remove obvious distractions from the user interface, learn the various technologies involved and lay the groundwork for future development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was started on Friday 5th July 2019 by a small group of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fediverse&#34;&gt;fediverse&lt;/a&gt; users who had never even set eyes on the upstream code before. Over the last four months we have been overwhelmed by the support we have received from over 1000 social media followers across &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/glimpse_editor&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://bobadon.co.uk/@glimpse&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, dozens of financial backers across Patreon and &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;Open Collective&lt;/a&gt;, and over 100 people who have joined &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/about/%5B#glimpse:matrix.org%5D(https://matrix.to/#/#glimpse:matrix.org)&#34;&gt;our public Matrix channel&lt;/a&gt; to volunteer their expertise and ensure we make good decisions. We would like to thank everyone that helped us achieve our objectives, and we hope we can keep the momentum going as we start to plan what comes next in Glimpse 0.2.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also pleased to announce that in October 2019 we &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse/expenses/10167&#34;&gt;donated $50 to the GNU Image Manipulation Program&lt;/a&gt; as part of our commitment to share a portion of the donations we receive for each new release with them. We hope in future this amount will increase and be augmented with new bug fixes and features from our own contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GNU/Linux users can install Glimpse 0.1.0 as a Flatpak from the Flathub repository. There are also a number of additional installation options for Linux detailed on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/downloads/&#34;&gt;Downloads&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows users can use an MSI file to install Glimpse 0.1.0 on 32-bit and 64-bit systems running Windows 7 or later. We chose that type of installer to assist businesses and schools using centralised software management systems. This can also be found on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/downloads/&#34;&gt;Downloads&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;known-issues&#34;&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We do not support MacOS at this time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The current Windows installer triggers security warnings because it has not been signed. We intend to provide a signed installer very soon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no native 64-bit installer for Windows (use the 32-bit one instead)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Man pages in the terminal have not been updated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compatibility with upstream offline help pages has not been tested&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some translations may still need updating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-features&#34;&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glimpse 0.1.0 is based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/news/2019/06/12/gimp-2-10-12-released/&#34;&gt;GNU Image Manipulation Program 2.10.12&lt;/a&gt;. It also uses the following dependency package versions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gegl.org/babl/&#34;&gt;BABL&lt;/a&gt; 0.1.68&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gegl.org/&#34;&gt;GEGL&lt;/a&gt; 0.4.16&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mypaint.org/&#34;&gt;MyPaint&lt;/a&gt; 1.3.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;graphical-user-interface&#34;&gt;Graphical User Interface:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translation files, code &amp;amp; build files updated so &amp;ldquo;Glimpse&amp;rdquo; is displayed
throughout the UI, executables and packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the default UI behaviour for a cleaner/more professional look&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaced application logo and window/taskbar icons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaced &amp;ldquo;wilber eek&amp;rdquo; logo with a new application logo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaced initial splash screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated upstream icon themes to include our own iconography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaced some links in the &amp;ldquo;Help&amp;rdquo; menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed links to upstream help pages and documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated the About window&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed code for upstream &amp;ldquo;easter eggs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactored version strings and compatibility notices in file save dialog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactored display text for plug-ins, extensions and procedures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modified preferences panel to re-brand &amp;ldquo;Debugging&amp;rdquo; section and removed
toolbar header checkbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-improvements&#34;&gt;Code Improvements:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactored the automated &amp;ldquo;authors&amp;rdquo; system for the Glimpse project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactored the build system for the Glimpse project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed some scripts and tooling we do not use with this fork&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated the Flatpak build process and removed webkit build step for dev builds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided support for Snapcrafters to package the code through their third
party distribution channel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Travis CI support to sanity check and test builds in version control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a new 32-bit Windows installer with the WiX toolset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;developer-assistance&#34;&gt;Developer Assistance:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added BABL, GEGl and MyPaint dependencies as git submodules pre-set at the
current tagged releases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vagrantup.com/&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; support so the code can be built
&amp;amp; run without needing to install the prerequisites on the host system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided comprehensive build documentation for Windows and Linux in the &lt;code&gt;HACKING&lt;/code&gt; file and at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Building_Glimpse&#34;&gt;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Building_Glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved integration with the GNOME Builder IDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided new code level documentation of our own (such as code of conduct,
contributing guide, changelog, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quality-of-life-improvements&#34;&gt;Quality of Life Improvements:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed legacy upstream documentation not needed for this fork&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed installation &amp;amp; configuration files location to avoid conflicts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed cached and temporary files location to avoid conflicts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed process identifiers so they do not conflict with other running
instances of the GNU Image Manipulation Program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added our own metadata for built and packaged executables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed &amp;ldquo;Color&amp;rdquo; icons (duplicates &amp;ldquo;Legacy&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed &amp;ldquo;Gray&amp;rdquo; UI theme (duplicates &amp;ldquo;System&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provided our own AppStream metadata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintained compatibility with existing GNU I.M.P v2.x plug-ins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactored &amp;ldquo;Created with GIMP&amp;rdquo; notice to &amp;ldquo;Created with Glimpse&amp;rdquo; in the
default save file metadata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaced Windows save file metadata icon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-branded categories used in Plug-in and Procedure browsers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank everyone who contributed towards making Glimpse 0.1.0 a success, particularly those unnamed individuals who spread the word about our project on social media, shared their feature requests with us and provided feedback to the development team during the beta testing phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;creator&#34;&gt;Creator&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bobby Moss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;maintainers&#34;&gt;Maintainers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christopher Davis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clipsey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-contributors&#34;&gt;Code Contributors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heather Ellsworth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;igalic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mathieu Bridon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;psymole&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;documentation-contributors&#34;&gt;Documentation Contributors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chaomodus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;melody&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;artwork-contributors&#34;&gt;Artwork Contributors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Daniel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;20-tier-sponsor-contributors&#34;&gt;$20+ Tier Sponsor Contributors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dominic Watson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kretz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loren Dias&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Massimo D&amp;rsquo;Ambrogio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roberts-Loux Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sami Mannila&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-tier-backers-and-one-off-donors&#34;&gt;$5+ Tier Backers and One-off Donors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to say a special thank you to all of our financial backers on &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;Open Collective&lt;/a&gt; and Patreon regardless of whether they are listed below or not. Without your help this release would not have been possible, and your continued support is highly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aalap Mogre&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brandon &amp;lsquo;Spanky&amp;rsquo; Mills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;G Cowell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gino H&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joe Mooring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kevin Rodriguez&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nitrohorse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pagrus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sam Muirhead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Samuel Pickard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stan Sorochan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transmutable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Violet Leonard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nearing Release</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/nearing-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/nearing-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Instead of providing a weekly reminder of our social media and project links across the web, check out our all-new &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt; page!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-tentatively-scheduled-for-friday-22nd-november-2019&#34;&gt;Release tentatively scheduled for Friday 22nd November 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the subtitle suggests we are &amp;ldquo;penciling in&amp;rdquo; a release date before the Thanksgiving holiday season in the United States. That is intended to assist our American contributors and ensure the release is not delayed because of winter festivities held around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are aiming for a &amp;ldquo;code freeze&amp;rdquo; on Monday 18th November 2019, and the timeline after that will depend on how quickly we can complete our documentation and how long it takes to submit Glimpse Image Editor to Flathub and the Windows Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank everyone who has donated and contributed to the Glimpse project so far, and encourage our supporters to help us now with a final push to make Glimpse available to the wider public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;snap-community-support-solved&#34;&gt;Snap community support solved&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to say that there will be a Snapcraft version of Glimpse 0.1 at launch! Thanks to the excellent efforts of Heather Ellsworth and psymole we now have changes merged into the codebase and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Building_Glimpse/Linux#Package_as_a_Snap&#34;&gt;a Wiki page&lt;/a&gt; explaining how to package our application as a Snap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;continued-work-on-the-windows-port&#34;&gt;Continued work on the Windows port&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss has been working through problems related to packaging Glimpse 0.1 for Windows systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately when Glimpse 0.1 launches it will not support Python plug-ins on Windows. This is due to a missing part of the upstream build instructions and we have been unable to find a workaround. JavaScript and Lua plug-ins are not affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately we were unable to acquire a CA validated code signing certificate for our Windows installers, meaning it will be blocked by Windows SmartScreen and your locally installed anti-virus program if you attempt to install it. This means that the 32-bit and 64-bit MSI installer files will only be released as a backup method for installing the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our intended workaround is to submit Glimpse Image Editor to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Store_(digital)&#34;&gt;the Windows Store&lt;/a&gt; and promote that as our primary supported method for downloading and installing our application on Windows. It will still be available for zero cost but it will fix the security warnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flatpak-improvements&#34;&gt;Flatpak improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathieu Bridon has continued to improve the Glimpse 0.1 BETA flatpak with new core dependency versions and updates to the metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can beta test the current flatpak release by following the instructions here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Testing_Glimpse&#34;&gt;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Testing_Glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;documentation-updates&#34;&gt;Documentation updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss has been drastically improving the code level documentation and Github integrations. Their pull request is not quite ready to merge yet, but you can follow it here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/214&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/214&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;website-updates&#34;&gt;Website updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Davis has been experimenting with new themes, website designs and accessibility changes. You can follow their progress here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/getglimpse-web/pull/54&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/getglimpse-web/pull/54&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The draft release notes and downloads page that Bobby Moss has been working can still be followed here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/getglimpse-web/pull/48&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/getglimpse-web/pull/48&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bug-fixes&#34;&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss has fixed a number of issues raised during beta testing such as &amp;ldquo;GIMP&amp;rdquo; still being used in recovery messages and the wrong logo being shown in the taskbar and window title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With assistance from Clipsey and Mathieu Bridon a fix has also been applied so Glimpse Image Editor can run at the same time as GNU Image Manipulation Program on a Windows machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-glimpse-naming-discussion-is-finally-over&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Glimpse&amp;rdquo; naming discussion is finally over!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have now &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues?page=2&amp;amp;q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aclosed&#34;&gt;closed the issue&lt;/a&gt; where people were robustly discussing if we should stick with &amp;ldquo;Glimpse&amp;rdquo; as a product name or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That controversy originally started after &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CV1HZU4KFHc&#34;&gt;a well-known YouTuber&lt;/a&gt; expressed negative opinions about our project&amp;rsquo;s name, and we spent &lt;em&gt;two entire weeks&lt;/em&gt; in August being aggressively lobbied around the clock on our communication channels by people repeating that YouTuber&amp;rsquo;s views to us verbatim, and subsequently having to deal with their frustration if we pointed out any flaws or practical issues with the points they were raising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As discussed on the Github issue we now treat &amp;ldquo;Glimpse&amp;rdquo; as a shortened version of &amp;ldquo;Glimpse Image Editor&amp;rdquo; and have changed our domain to glimpse-editor.org (with a matching .com) to address the legitimate concerns that were raised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months we have reviewed workable alternative suggestions we received on our Matrix channel, and we assisted the original poster with hosting a spreadsheet to assess support for a name change and any proposed alternatives. It was ultimately determined that there was very little internal support in favor of changing the name within the project, and no compelling alternative was ever produced. We also heard the feedback from our social media followers telling us that we need to draw a line under this discussion so we can focus more of our efforts on producing an excellent fork of the GNU Image Manipulation Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank everyone for their patience as this discussion slowly made its way through our project&amp;rsquo;s system of governance. It received more attention and scrutiny than any other issue we have so far discussed, and we hope that is some consolation to anyone that is disappointed with the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reminder-patreon-campaign-to-be-closed-in-december-2019&#34;&gt;REMINDER: Patreon campaign to be closed in December 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank everyone who has contributed cash to the project on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt; page since its inception in July 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned in previous posts we have created a new fundraising campaign on &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;Open Collective&lt;/a&gt;. This is great for you as followers of our project because you can choose between a one-off or monthly donation, see how much we receive and what we spend your money on, and (if you live in the US) benefit from tax deductions. From the project&amp;rsquo;s point of view the charity behind the platform provides us with legal/financial services and ensures our expense claims are legitimate. Open Collective also enables more than one person to run the fundraising campaign and track backer rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know the project will probably take a financial hit when we do this, but we feel this is the right long term decision because it will reduce the administrative overhead our core contributors have to deal with and better ensure accountability within our project&amp;rsquo;s governance structure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beta Testing Underway</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/beta-testing-underway/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/beta-testing-underway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Instead of providing a weekly reminder of our social media and project links across the web, check out our all-new &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt; page!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-release-schedule-update&#34;&gt;Another release schedule update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately we are going to miss our target of releasing in October 2019. We made that estimate before beta testing had started and also when our packaging efforts were still in their very early stages, so this was not unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that will be disappointing to hear for many of you reading this, but as with any new free software project setbacks and &amp;ldquo;blockers&amp;rdquo; like this are to be expected. We apologize, but also take solace in the fact that this project has only existed since Friday 5th July 2019. The amount we have achieved in less than four months has been quite remarkable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Glimpse project would like to thank the community for your continued support and patience with us. We will provide an update some time in the middle of November 2019 to confirm if we will be formally releasing before the end of that month or in the first half of December 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;snap-support-stalled&#34;&gt;Snap support stalled&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately (at the time when this blog post was published) there had been no updates made to the related pull request for two weeks: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/153&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/153&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think you can pick this work up and finish it then please get in touch with us! If we cannot complete this task then we will need to bring forward plans to also package Glimpse 0.1 as an &lt;a href=&#34;https://appimage.org/&#34;&gt;AppImage&lt;/a&gt; so that Linux users will still have an alternative for systems that do not support Flatpak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;continued-work-on-the-windows-port&#34;&gt;Continued work on the Windows port&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss has been working through problems related to packaging Glimpse 0.1 for Windows systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a new Windows installer from scratch has proved difficult because of the sheer number of dependency files involved, but we are confident the end result will be worth it. Bobby has succeeded in producing a 32-bit MSI file that should work on all Windows systems from Windows 7 or later. You can find new instructions for this here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Testing_Glimpse&#34;&gt;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Testing_Glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A roadblock we have run into is that (much like the ZIP files produced at the start of beta testing) this new installer triggers warnings and blocks from Windows User Account Control, Windows SmartScreen and any other locally installed anti-virus program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the development releases will always have this problem (even if we use a self-signed certificate), that is clearly not acceptable for formal releases. We will need to buy a three year code signing certificate &lt;a href=&#34;https://comodosslstore.com/codesigning.aspx&#34;&gt;from a reputable CA&lt;/a&gt; to fix that problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our efforts to automate the building and packaging of the Windows port on &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins.glimpse-editor.org/&#34;&gt;our Jenkins server&lt;/a&gt; have stalled. We are still puzzling out the documented cross-compilation steps from upstream and how to script the packaging process with &lt;a href=&#34;https://wixtoolset.org/&#34;&gt;the WiX Toolset&lt;/a&gt;. However that will not be done in time for the 0.1 release, so currently the Windows build and packaging process relies entirely on one person (Bobby Moss) doing it all manually, and that is not a small task!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In more positive news, we have confirmed that GNU Image Manipulation Program 2.10.12 and Glimpse 0.1 BETA can both be installed alongside each other on the same Windows system without sharing or overwriting each others&amp;rsquo; configuration files. You cannot currently launch one while the other is still running, but we are working on a fix for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a full list of Windows bugs and &amp;ldquo;known issues&amp;rdquo; we are currently aware of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BETA builds trigger security warnings from Windows and anti-virus programs &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/195&#34;&gt;195&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glimpse 0.1 BETA is currently built without Python support due to this being missing in upstream documentation, so a noticeable number of plug-ins are not loaded by the application when it is started &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/178&#34;&gt;178&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Wilber icon is still shown in the taskbar and window title when a file is open and being modified &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/176&#34;&gt;176&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Wilber icon and upstream application name is still shown in error messages and recovery dialogs &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/190&#34;&gt;190&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offline help files are not included with this release &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/145&#34;&gt;145&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glimpse 0.1 BETA and GNU Image Manipulation Program 2.10.12 can be installed alongside each other but cannot run at the same time. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/196&#34;&gt;196&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flatpak-improvements&#34;&gt;Flatpak improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathieu Bridon has continued to improve the Glimpse 0.1 BETA flatpak with new core dependency versions and updates to the metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can beta test the current flatpak release by following the instructions here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Testing_Glimpse&#34;&gt;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Testing_Glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;documentation-updates&#34;&gt;Documentation updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss has been improving the code level documentation. Their pull request is not quite ready to merge yet, but you can follow it here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/188&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/188&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glimpse project also confirmed that the Glimpse logo and assets are provided under a Creative Commons (&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;) license. Clarifications have also been made to the &lt;code&gt;LICENSE&lt;/code&gt; file in the root of the source code in &lt;code&gt;dev-g210&lt;/code&gt; branch: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/187&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/187&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;website-updates&#34;&gt;Website updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Davis has been experimenting with new themes, website designs and accessibility changes. You can follow their progress here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/getglimpse-web/pull/54&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/getglimpse-web/pull/54&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The draft release notes and downloads page that Bobby Moss has been working can still be followed here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/getglimpse-web/pull/48&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/getglimpse-web/pull/48&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;patreon-campaign-to-be-closed-in-december-2019&#34;&gt;Patreon campaign to be closed in December 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank everyone who has contributed cash to the project on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt; page since its inception in July 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned in previous posts we have created a new fundraising campaign on &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;Open Collective&lt;/a&gt;. This is great for you as followers of our project because you can choose between a one-off or monthly donation, see how much we receive and what we spend your money on, and (if you live in the US) benefit from tax deductions. From the project&amp;rsquo;s point of view the charity behind the platform provides us with legal/financial services and ensures our expense claims are legitimate. Open Collective also enables more than one person to run the fundraising campaign and track backer rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know the project will probably take a financial hit when we do this, but we feel this is the right long term decision because it will reduce the administrative overhead our core contributors have to deal with and better ensure accountability within our project&amp;rsquo;s governance structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is positive feedback for the idea, we may also encourage individual contributors to host their own Patreon campaigns and PayPal links so they can still receive contributions from those of you who prefer those platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-numbering-change&#34;&gt;Release numbering change&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a related note, the project has also changed its future development plans based on what we have collectively learned over the last few months. We originally intended that 0.x would be based on GNU Image Manipulation Program 2.10.x, 1.x would be based on GNU Image Manipulation Program 3.x, and 2.x would be our own rewrite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have made the decision to not re-fork the GNU Image Manipulation Program when it reaches version 3.x. Realistically, we do not have the people and resources needed to recreate all the changes and tooling we have produced over the last four months again to make that major update (and its entirely new build processes) a worthwhile end product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead we believe it makes more sense to stick to the 2.10.x base, and make that as stable and &amp;ldquo;long term supportable&amp;rdquo; as possible while also adding our own changes to it. 1.0 should be released towards the second half of 2020, assuming the 0.x releases that are produced before then are stable and well-received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;UI rewrite&amp;rdquo; running in parallel will continue unhindered, and we hope to see some initial alpha-level prototypes some time in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reaching-out-to-facebook-users&#34;&gt;Reaching out to Facebook users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will now find the Glimpse project &lt;a href=&#34;https://fb.me/glimpse.editor&#34;&gt;on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. Bobby Moss is currently maintaining that page, and this is another part of our outreach efforts to users outside the free software community. It should also assist with our efforts to improve the project&amp;rsquo;s search engine optimization (SEO).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this &lt;a href=&#34;https://bobadon.co.uk/@glimpse&#34;&gt;our Mastodon account&lt;/a&gt; will continue to be our primary social media channel. The Glimpse project spawned from the fediverse, so it will always be our preference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-work-on-the-ui-rewrite&#34;&gt;Early work on the UI rewrite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seems to be early support around the idea of using the D programming language with a recent version of GTK to produce this UI rewrite. You can see some of the early design work from people like meltheadorable on our wiki: &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Main_Page&#34;&gt;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Main_Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luna (Clipsey) has been experimenting with GTK bindings for D in her own Github project space. She has been regularly posting screenshots of that work in the (invite-only) &amp;ldquo;Glimpse 2.x UI Rewrite&amp;rdquo; Matrix channel, and you can check that code out for yourself here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Member1221/d-dazzle&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Member1221/d-dazzle&lt;/a&gt; and here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Member1221/d-handy&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Member1221/d-handy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaomodus has also been preparing to contribute to this parallel effort by teaching themselves the D programming language in their spare time, and rewriting simple UNIX utilities as a learning exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nearly Beta-Ready</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/nearly-beta-ready/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/nearly-beta-ready/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Instead of providing a weekly reminder of our social media and project links across the web, check out our all-new &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt; page!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-release-schedule-update&#34;&gt;Another release schedule update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The target date for Glimpse 0.1 to be &amp;ldquo;officially&amp;rdquo; released is some time this month (October 2019). However, you do not need to wait much longer to try the software out for yourself as we now have some beta testing builds for Windows and Linux!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still actively working on the packaging for Glimpse 0.1 and will continue to update the instructions you need to test pre-release versions of the software. Our initial instructions are available here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Testing_Glimpse&#34;&gt;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Testing_Glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please report any problems you find with our beta builds here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;snap-support-coming-soon&#34;&gt;Snap support coming soon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;psymole, EndrII and Heather Ellsworth have been doing some fantastic work ensuring we can build Glimpse with &lt;a href=&#34;https://snapcraft.io/&#34;&gt;snapcraft&lt;/a&gt;. We previously believed we would not be able to support that packaging format, but thanks to their efforts it should be ready by the time Glimpse 0.1 is released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow their progress inside this merge request: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/153&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/153&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;continued-work-on-the-windows-port&#34;&gt;Continued work on the Windows port&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss has been working through problems related to packaging Glimpse 0.1 for Windows systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Building_Glimpse/Windows&#34;&gt;build process&lt;/a&gt; we currently follow dynamically links with components from MinGW, so time was set aside to determine which dependencies we needed to bundle with Glimpse and to verify that the licenses relating to those components permitted us to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have succeeded in creating a pair of ZIP files for Windows 7 or newer, with one being for 32-bit systems and the other for 64-bit. These have been provided as a stop-gap measure until we have working MSI installers and portable executables to publish within the next couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flatpak-improvements&#34;&gt;Flatpak improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathieu Bridon has successfully removed the Webkit dependency from our flatpak development builds. This makes builds much faster and reduces the load from the job they produced for our &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins.glimpse-editor.org&#34;&gt;Jenkins CI server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;website-updates&#34;&gt;Website updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss has been drafting the release notes for Glimpse 0.1.0 and a future &amp;ldquo;downloads&amp;rdquo; page. You can follow their progress here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/getglimpse-web/pull/48&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/getglimpse-web/pull/48&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now also type &lt;code&gt;www.&lt;/code&gt; at the start of our URL and still be redirected to the right place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Davis has set up an automated staging and testing process for this website using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.netlify.com/&#34;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt; in preparation for further development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-you-help-exiv2&#34;&gt;Can you help Exiv2?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We and a number of other free software projects depend on a project that is currently in a state of limbo. If you think you can help, the Exiv2 team urgently need your assistance: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Exiv2/exiv2/issues/1018&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Exiv2/exiv2/issues/1018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closing Out September</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/closing-out-september/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/closing-out-september/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Instead of providing a weekly reminder of our social media and project links across the web, check out our all-new &lt;a href=&#34;../../contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt; page!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;updated-release-schedule&#34;&gt;Updated release schedule&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been working hard over the last two weeks, and we aim to provide beta test releases for Windows and Linux before the end of September 2019. With the help of our supporters trying them out when they are made available and reporting bugs they find we can expect to officially release Glimpse 0.1.0 around the middle of October 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We apologise for the delay, but we believe it is important to release a robust application that people can use as a drop-in replacement for GNU Image Manipulation Program 2.10.12 and start working with as their daily driver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glimpse also does not have an internal update mechanism and could be deployed on centrally managed systems in schools and workplaces where stability is highly valued, so we do not feel that &amp;ldquo;release early, patch often&amp;rdquo; is the right approach for this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of our core contributors thank you for your patience, and we will continue to work hard to make sure that Glimpse 0.1.0 achieves our stated objectives and makes you proud to support us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;help-wanted&#34;&gt;Help wanted&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work on a Linux AppImage has not yet started, so if you would like to try your hand at packaging then this Github issue is a great starting point: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/108&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/108&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally for those who still have concerns about our project name, the original poster of this Github issue is now hosting an unofficial spreadsheet to gather suggestions and informally canvas opinion on our behalf: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/92&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/92&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;porting-to-windows&#34;&gt;Porting to Windows&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss has been focussing most of his development time and energy over the past week on porting Glimpse to the Windows platform. You can see the progress they are making here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/152&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/152&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing our current plan is to port the upstream process for creating an installer. If that proves to be problematic then we will switch back to our previous plan of writing our own bespoke installer for Glimpse using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wixtoolset.org/&#34;&gt;WiX toolset&lt;/a&gt; as described here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/119&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/119&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of building the code on Windows using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.msys2.org/&#34;&gt;MSYS2&lt;/a&gt; has been documented here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Building_Glimpse/Windows&#34;&gt;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Building_Glimpse/Windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;documentation-updates&#34;&gt;Documentation updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss and Mathieu Bridon have created an excellent new section on the wiki that comprehensively covers how to build and package Glimpse on Linux and Windows. They have also added instructions for how to build the code from IDEs like &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.gnome.org/Apps/Builder&#34;&gt;GNOME Builder&lt;/a&gt; on Linux and &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt; on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope you will find this useful, and you can see their work here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Building_Glimpse&#34;&gt;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org/index.php?title=Building_Glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-changes&#34;&gt;Code changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss added support for &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/branches&#34;&gt;Travis CI&lt;/a&gt; so that every new commit and pull request is automatically sanity checked with a build before it is merged. Mathieu Bridon is currently working to enhance this by ensuring that unit tests are also run against the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss also updated the code so that our new splash screen and application icons are used throughout the application. They also fixed bugs related to folder locations and processes clashing with past or existing installations of the GNU Image Manipulation Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathieu Bridon has cleared away redundant files and been updating the metadata files used by GNOME desktop and Flatpak to ensure Linux users have an optimal experience when we release Glimpse 0.1.0. We look forward to him assisting us when we push the latest build to &lt;a href=&#34;https://flathub.org/&#34;&gt;Flathub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;psymole and EndrII have also been working together to add &lt;a href=&#34;https://snapcraft.io/&#34;&gt;Snap&lt;/a&gt; support to the current codebase. We did not expect to be able to support this technology in time for Glimpse 0.1.0, so we are deeply grateful for their efforts: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/153&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/pull/153&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-decisions&#34;&gt;Project decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see which work items are still outstanding for Glimpse 0.1.0 here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/milestone/1&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/milestone/1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In anticipation of us releasing Glimpse 0.1.0 we have donated $50 of backer funds to the GNU Image Manipulation Program. That exceeds our stated pledge that at least 10% of the funds we receive for this release will be donated to the upstream project. You can see a full accounting of the donations we have received and how we have started to spend them on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;Open Collective&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Glimpse project also participated in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital.globalclimatestrike.net/&#34;&gt;Digital Climate Strike&lt;/a&gt; on Friday 20th September 2019 to show our support and solidarity with demonstrations being held around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;website-updates&#34;&gt;Website updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a number of people provided feedback about it we updated the subtitle on the Glimpse home page to make our objectives clear. It now reads &amp;ldquo;Glimpse is an open source image editor based on the GNU Image Manipulation Program. The goal is to experiment with new ideas and expand the use of free software.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Davis has also taken on the task of redesigning our project website. We anticipate improvements to the overall layout and design in the weeks and months ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss has also started drafting the Glimpse 0.1.0 release post and our new downloads page. You can preview that work here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/getglimpse-web/pull/48&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/getglimpse-web/pull/48&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dropped-support-for-apple-macos&#34;&gt;Dropped support for Apple MacOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately at the time of writing the upstream documentation for &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.gimp.org/wiki/Hacking:_Building/Mac_OSX&#34;&gt;building on OSX&lt;/a&gt; is quite sparse and does not seem to have been updated since it was first created in April 2011. As a result we have had to do our own research to figure out how that works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research sadly did not yield the right answer, despite our core contributors committing whole weeks of time to working on the problem and reading through old Github repositories, forums and community blog posts. The closest we came to a solution was finding an &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.gnome.org/Infrastructure/gimp-macos-build&#34;&gt;upstream experiment with CircleCI&lt;/a&gt;, but this seems to be a very early work-in-progress and our own attempts to get it working using more cost-effective local tools did not succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After further review we determined that even if we reached out to the upstream project to find out how to build Glimpse 0.1 for MacOS, we do not have anyone with the right combination of skills, equipment, enthusiasm and free time to keep that build maintained over a sustained period of time. We concluded that focussing our efforts on the Linux and Windows ports instead best serves the most number of people with the limited resources available to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we know that will come as a disappointment for many of you, we hope that &lt;a href=&#34;http://libregraphicsworld.org/blog/entry/meet-seashore-free-image-editor-for-macos&#34;&gt;SeaShore&lt;/a&gt; will prove to be a viable substitute we can recommend. We believe it fits the criteria of being a re-branded variant of the GNU Image Manipulation Program with a better GUI, and it also benefits from being mature, well-maintained, available for zero cost through the Apple App Store and developed specifically for use with MacOS. Give it a try, and let us know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-news&#34;&gt;Other news&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are aware that an enthusiastic member of the Arch community has created an AUR package that links to the Glimpse project&amp;rsquo;s development branch. If you would like to preview the latest changes and are using a compatible GNU/Linux distribution then that is an exciting new unofficial installation option.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Transparency And Automation</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/more-transparency-and-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 22:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/more-transparency-and-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Instead of providing a weekly reminder of our social media and project links across the web, check out our all-new &lt;a href=&#34;../../contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt; page!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still on schedule to release Glimpse 0.1 some time in September 2019. The application is mostly code-complete, so the outstanding work items primarily relate to artwork, packaging and automated builds. Minor patches may also still be applied for code cleanup and documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;glimpse-project-adopts-open-collective&#34;&gt;Glimpse project adopts Open Collective&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After feedback from the community asking us to support more donation methods, we have now setup an account on &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;Open Collective&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great thing about this service is that as supporters and users of Glimpse 0.1 you will be able see how much we receive in donations and how we use those funds to advance the project. It also means the business and legal side of receiving donations is taken care of for us by a well-known US-based charity, and more than one person can administer the funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will continue to support Patreon donations for the foreseeable future, but periodically those funds will need to be transferred across to Open Collective. Switching across from Patreon gives you the option of sending one-off instead of monthly donations, is tax-deductible (in the US) and saves the project money on transfer fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information: &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/glimpse/updates/welcome-to-the-glimpse-open-collective-profile&#34;&gt;https://opencollective.com/glimpse/updates/welcome-to-the-glimpse-open-collective-profile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-started-on-travis-ci-integration&#34;&gt;Work started on Travis CI integration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on a great suggestion from Mathieu Bridon, Bobby Moss has ported the Linux build instructions to Travis-CI and started testing automated builds using the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is still a work in progress as Bobby wants to setup the publishing steps for Windows, Mac and Linux in the same build file. You can take a look at the latest progress here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/tree/travis-ci&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/tree/travis-ci&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-project-logo&#34;&gt;New project logo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are very grateful to the amazing &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesdaniel.dev/&#34;&gt;James Daniel&lt;/a&gt; for working with us to produce our project logo. We have finally banished the public domain question mark we were using as a placeholder to the dustbin of history!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also produced new icons for us to use for the application launcher and throughout the project. These have not yet been applied to the codebase and we are still working on usage guidelines, but you can see a preview of that work here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/branding&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/branding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-changes&#34;&gt;Code changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dominic Watson added the Glimpse project &lt;a href=&#34;../../code-of-conduct/&#34;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt; on this website to the codebase as &lt;code&gt;CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss completed his previous work removing Wilber&amp;rsquo;s eyes and flashing red &amp;ldquo;jump scare&amp;rdquo; easter egg from the main window after receiving feedback from XenonFiber about a patch submitted upstream. He also updated the code level documentation and &amp;ldquo;Help&amp;rdquo; links to include the new web domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also saw some interesting new UI concepts from marcato10 and taciturasa that were assessed and discussed by the 2.x UI rewrite stream running in parallel to current development efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-decisions&#34;&gt;Project decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unascribed raised the issue that the hash values in our code&amp;rsquo;s commit tree do not match upstream. The project determined that the fix for this was &amp;ldquo;high impact with low benefit&amp;rdquo;, so decided against doing so. Users are advised that they can still run &lt;code&gt;diff&lt;/code&gt; on the commit tree and files to verify file integrity. More information: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/132&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/132&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project also discussed where to host the release executables for Glimpse 0.1. The Linux packages are likely to be hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://flathub.org/home&#34;&gt;Flathub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://appimage.github.io/&#34;&gt;AppImageHub&lt;/a&gt;, while the Mac and Windows packages will most likely be mirrored from a Github release tag. We are also investigating what is required for us to support torrent files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also agreed and implemented the new artwork and Open Collective account discussed earlier in this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;website-updates&#34;&gt;Website updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss updated the &lt;a href=&#34;../../contribute/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt; page so it grouped things together a little better and provided new donate links. He also added a new default favicon based on the new project logo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Second Month Closes</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/a-second-month-closes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 19:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/a-second-month-closes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a quick reminder of where you can find us on social media and our project tools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/glimpse_editor&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/glimpse_editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fediverse: &lt;a href=&#34;https://bobadon.co.uk/@glimpse&#34;&gt;https://bobadon.co.uk/@glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patreon: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;https://www.patreon.com/glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matrix: &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.to/#/#glimpse:matrix.org&#34;&gt;https://matrix.to/#/#glimpse:matrix.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wiki: &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org&#34;&gt;https://wiki.glimpse-editor.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FAQs: &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/about/&#34;&gt;https://glimpse-editor.org/about/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also encourage those who can to donate to the GNU Image Manipulation Program, as that funds the components Glimpse depends on: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/donating/&#34;&gt;https://www.gimp.org/donating/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;addressing-a-common-misconception&#34;&gt;Addressing a common misconception&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to take a moment to clarify that contrary to what some of you may have heard we did not &amp;ldquo;split from&amp;rdquo; the GNU Image Manipulation Program, and their project&amp;rsquo;s resources have not been &amp;ldquo;divided&amp;rdquo; between us both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Glimpse project is made up of a group of enthusiasts from outside the upstream project running their own fork and learning the codebase as they work on it. The same contributors that originally developed the GNU Image Manipulation Program are still doing so now and are entirely unimpeded by this fork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, read this FAQ: &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/about/#do-you-intend-to-replace-the-gnu-image-manipulation-program&#34;&gt;https://glimpse-editor.org/about/#do-you-intend-to-replace-the-gnu-image-manipulation-program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-were-discussed-on-the-register&#34;&gt;We were discussed on The Register&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss was interviewed by Tim Anderson, and you can read the resulting article here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/08/28/gimp_open_source_image_editor_forked_to_fix_problematic_name/&#34;&gt;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/08/28/gimp_open_source_image_editor_forked_to_fix_problematic_name/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-glimpse-name-was-discussed-in-detail&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Glimpse&amp;rdquo; name was discussed in detail&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have opened a Github issue for the community to provide suggestions and discuss new names here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/92&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/92&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After several days of intense discussion on Matrix it was determined that &amp;ldquo;Glimpse&amp;rdquo; should be treated as a code name for the 0.x &amp;ldquo;soft fork&amp;rdquo; releases based on the GNU Image Manipulation Program v2. A potential change of name would be applied from 1.0, the first release that &amp;ldquo;hard forks&amp;rdquo; from GNU Image Manipulation Program v3 (scheduled some time in 2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making the decision on whether we should change the name a &amp;ldquo;blocking&amp;rdquo; issue for 0.1 turned out to be a major distraction that could have delayed our first binary release indefinitely, so we feel that allowing more time to find a solution is a sensible compromise. Debate on this subject is still permitted on the &lt;strong&gt;#glimpse:matrix.org&lt;/strong&gt; (or &amp;ldquo;Glimpse Community&amp;rdquo;) Matrix channel so long as it does not filibuster other project decisions and day-to-day business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If an alternative our community supports and does not clash with other organizations/projects/applications is found before 1.0 is released then the name will be changed. If a new name that fulfils that criteria cannot be found in time, then we believe there is enough support within the project and wider community for us to consider the matter settled and stick with &amp;ldquo;Glimpse Image Editor&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-changes&#34;&gt;Code changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss updated the code-level documentation. &lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt; no longer links to an IRC channel we do not support anymore, &lt;code&gt;NEWS&lt;/code&gt; lists all the code level changes made so far and &lt;code&gt;HACKING&lt;/code&gt; has been updated with Glimpse-specific instructions. He has also started working on the macOS build and packaging process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-decisions&#34;&gt;Project decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was further discussion on the choice of programming language for the 2.x &amp;ldquo;UI Rewrite&amp;rdquo; stream running in parallel. There was a considerable uptick in support for using D instead of Rust in the comments section of this Github issue: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/70&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/70&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further progress was made on the application logo and icon designs. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rakujira&#34;&gt;Jaames&lt;/a&gt; made some interesting suggestions and has started developing those ideas for us. We look forward to seeing what they come up with!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also determined that we should pledge to donate at least 10% of the Patreon donations we receive for each new release to the GNU Image Manipulation Program as a way of saying thank you for the contributions our fork relies on. That will be in addition to any other contributions we assist them with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;website-updates&#34;&gt;Website updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bobby Moss updated the FAQs page to reflect recent project decisions and elaborate on how the Glimpse project is governed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clipsey wrote a new page with handy links for potential contributors: &lt;a href=&#34;https://glimpse-editor.org/contribute/&#34;&gt;https://glimpse-editor.org/contribute/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Melody generously donated the glimpse-editor.org and glimpse-editor.com domains to the project to fix the clash between getglimpse.app and getglimpse.com.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The project received several offers to help with the overall website design, and we look forward to seeing the results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are Getting Noticed</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/we-are-getting-noticed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 19:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/we-are-getting-noticed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are new to our project, welcome! Here is a quick reminder of where you can find us on social media and our project tools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/glimpse_editor&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/glimpse_editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fediverse: &lt;a href=&#34;https://bobadon.co.uk/@glimpse&#34;&gt;https://bobadon.co.uk/@glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patreon: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;https://www.patreon.com/glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matrix: &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.to/#/#glimpse:matrix.org&#34;&gt;https://matrix.to/#/#glimpse:matrix.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wiki: &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.getglimpse.app&#34;&gt;https://wiki.getglimpse.app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also encourage those who can to donate to the GNU Image Manipulation Program, as that funds the components Glimpse depends on: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/donating/&#34;&gt;https://www.gimp.org/donating/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;glimpse-discussed-on-youtube&#34;&gt;Glimpse discussed on YouTube&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest update this week was been the project gaining the attention of two prominent YouTubers in the Linux community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bryan Lunduke&lt;/strong&gt; (65,000 subscribers) published a video called &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The GIMP has been forked by folks who find the name offensive&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/CV1HZU4KFHc&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/CV1HZU4KFHc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After seeing Bryan&amp;rsquo;s video we have taken his feedback on board and temporarily made &lt;code&gt;dev-g210&lt;/code&gt; the default branch so people can more easily find our in-development changes. We disagree that &amp;ldquo;Glimpse&amp;rdquo; is a bad name, but have opened a Github Issue for people who would like to suggest alternatives we can put to the community here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/92&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/92&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gardiner &amp;ldquo;The Linux Gamer&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; (47,000 subscribers) published a video called &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why are people FREAKING OUT about Glimpse?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/CbxvaC9fo4g&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/CbxvaC9fo4g&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone on Matrix chat appreciated the sentiments Gardiner expressed in that video, and the Glimpse project also encourages everyone in our own community to support each other and be kind to people who may have opinions that differ from our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank Bryan and Gardiner for their even-handed reviews of the issues and for encouraging their viewers to remain civil. The Glimpse project and individuals involved with it have periodically been on the receiving end of targetted harassment since its inception, but we are relieved to report no increase since those videos were released. We were also pleased to see that regardless of their opinions about our fork the vast majority of people on social media have been constructive and respectful to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like their work, you can find donation links here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bryan Lunduke: &lt;a href=&#34;http://lunduke.com/&#34;&gt;http://lunduke.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gardiner &amp;ldquo;The Linux Gamer&amp;rdquo;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/thelinuxgamer&#34;&gt;https://www.patreon.com/thelinuxgamer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;glimpse-mentioned-on-omg-ubuntu&#34;&gt;Glimpse mentioned on &amp;ldquo;OMG! Ubuntu!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the article here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2019/08/glimpse-gimp-image-editor-fork&#34;&gt;https://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2019/08/glimpse-gimp-image-editor-fork&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very cool to see our project start to attract the attention of major Linux news outlets at such an early stage in its development. We would also like to thank them for linking to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse&#34;&gt;Github project&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;Patreon donation page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;glimpse-also-mentioned-on-its-foss&#34;&gt;Glimpse also mentioned on &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s FOSS&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the article here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://itsfoss.com/gimp-fork-glimpse/&#34;&gt;https://itsfoss.com/gimp-fork-glimpse/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a well-researched and thoughtful article we enjoyed reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-logo-ideas&#34;&gt;More logo ideas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;will&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;measly twerp&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;jwhkvthdi&amp;rdquo; posted some interesting logo ideas and concept artwork in the Matrix chat. We appreciate their contributions and warmly welcome them to our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss particularly enjoyed the pagan mascot idea from Chris Tallerås here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.art/@ChrisTalleras/102684102318412133&#34;&gt;https://mastodon.art/@ChrisTalleras/102684102318412133&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-changes&#34;&gt;Code changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss reinstated the &amp;ldquo;Dark&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Light&amp;rdquo; UI themes, as well as the &amp;ldquo;Symbolic&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Symbolic-Inverted&amp;rdquo; icons. (The &amp;ldquo;Gray&amp;rdquo; UI theme and &amp;ldquo;Color&amp;rdquo; icons have been left out as we do not believe they add any value beyond what the existing &amp;ldquo;System&amp;rdquo; UI them and &amp;ldquo;Legacy&amp;rdquo; icons provide)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-decisions&#34;&gt;Project decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We collectively agreed that because GTK2 applications look out-of-place on some operating systems we should choose the default UI theme and icon set that best fits with the operating system we publish binaries for. This is intended as a temporary measure until upstream finishes the port to GTK3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melody stepped down as a moderator on our Matrix channels. The project thanks her for the contributions she has made so far and is excited to see the design activities she is working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also agreed that we should determine whether to squash commits in a pull request after consulting the original poster. In some cases contributors may have taken care to make atomic, buildable commits in their Git history and we should take this into account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris and Clipsey also produced mockups for a potential new &amp;ldquo;Welcome screen&amp;rdquo; that could replace the default splash screen after the hard fork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;website-updates&#34;&gt;Website updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss updated the FAQs page and added two new answers for project-related questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martijn Braam also added a subtitle to our homepage so newcomers can see a one-line summary clarifying the Glimpse project&amp;rsquo;s purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six Week Checkpoint</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/six-week-checkpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 17:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/six-week-checkpoint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a busy couple of weeks! Thank you for bearing with us while we continue to work hard on producing the first Glimpse release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now expect it to arrive some time in September 2019. Our developers are still puzzling out how to package the built code for different operating systems, and the artwork for the rebrand is not quite ready yet. Despite this, you can expect there to be a code freeze before the end of August 2019 so we can focus our energies on solving both of those problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-changes&#34;&gt;Code changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathieu Bridon has been updating the Flatpak packaging our Linux build will rely on. He is also fixing GNOME desktop integrations for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss helped newcomers to the codebase at Clipsey&amp;rsquo;s suggestion by adding the GEGL, BABL and MyPaint dependencies as submodules. He also added Vagrant support so newcomers can get a working build environment up-and-running as quickly as possible. To build our code and then run the current in-development version of Glimpse (you will need &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/projects/xming/&#34;&gt;an XServer installed&lt;/a&gt; for the final command if you are not using Linux as a host):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;$ vagrant up
$ vagrant ssh
$ cd /vagrant
$ sh glimpse-vagrant.sh
$ ./glimpse-prefix/bin/glimpse
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bobby also provisioned a new Jenkins build server at &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins.getglimpse.app&#34;&gt;https://jenkins.getglimpse.app&lt;/a&gt; and will be implementing an automated build job for the Glimpse source code over the next week or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-new-versioning-scheme&#34;&gt;A new versioning scheme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discussed as a community how we should version and market our fork over the coming months and years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glimpse 0.1 is the first release, scheduled for some time in September 2019, and further &amp;ldquo;soft fork&amp;rdquo; releases will start with 0.x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glimpse 1.0 will be the first &amp;ldquo;hard fork&amp;rdquo;. We expect this to be fully ported to GTK3 and provide its own Documentation. It likely won&amp;rsquo;t happen until GNU Image Manipulation Program 3.0 has been released some time in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further &amp;ldquo;hard fork&amp;rdquo; releases will start with 1.x, and these will have more ambitious changes that do not need to be re-applied to an upstream codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As discussed in the last post there will also be a front-end UI rewrite happening in parallel. The name for this has not yet been confirmed, but initially it will have versions that start with 2.x as the plan would be to switch over to it once it achieves feature parity with the current application. We estimate that will take until 2021 to achieve even if we started right away, but the long term benefit would be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plans-for-the-distant-future&#34;&gt;Plans for the distant future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaomodus has continued to develop the new MediaWiki server at &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.getglimpse.app&#34;&gt;https://wiki.getglimpse.app&lt;/a&gt;, and they along with meltheadorable, Christopher Davis and others have been examining which plug-ins we should keep or remove in subsequent 0.x releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those same people have used the same server to upload screenshots of existing image editing application user interfaces. This is intended to help them analyse what is good and bad about current image editing applications, then produce their own design mockups to compare and discuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choice of programming language for the rewrite was also discussed. That is being tracked on this Github issue: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/70&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/70&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;website-updates&#34;&gt;Website updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website is now hosted on the new Jenkins build server. This ensures we keep our costs low and that our website re-builds properly when we add new posts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Completing Our First Month</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/completing-our-first-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 18:50:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/completing-our-first-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we approach the end of this project&amp;rsquo;s first month we would like to thank everyone that has gotten involved, contributed to and supported this project so far. The wider community&amp;rsquo;s enthusiasm for Glimpse has been amazing to see, and we hope we can keep that energy going through August and produce our first stable release very soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us proceed with the latest updates from week 4!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-changes&#34;&gt;Code changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We changed the name of our current development branch based on the GNU Image Manipulation Project 2.10.12 codebase from &amp;ldquo;gimp2-10&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;dev-g210&amp;rdquo; so its purpose is clearer to new project members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss cleared away more redundant UI themes, updated the web links in the Help menu and fixed the application name displayed when you create a new image or see error messages. He also updated his &amp;ldquo;helper scripts&amp;rdquo; after feedback from joshg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathieu Bridon has started sharing the Flatpak build fixes he previously submitted upstream with us, and igalic reviewed the existing code build steps and fixed the name of the final executable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-decisions&#34;&gt;Community Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a lot of discussion about a potential rewrite of the codebase, and you can read more about the results of that in the &amp;ldquo;Future Plans After Glimpse 2.0&amp;rdquo; section of this blog post. We also decided to postpone any decision on the choice of language for any potential future rewrite until criteria have been determined for that decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also considered whether Github was still an appropriate place to host our code and feature/bug tracking issues. There seems to be no great desire to switch to another platform, but we have had offers to share infrastructure with other projects if we ever change our mind (eg. GNOME project have offered us space in the &amp;ldquo;world&amp;rdquo; namespace, and Florence project have offered us access to their Gitea server)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issues and milestones we have on Github were also rearranged to confirm our current understanding about the project&amp;rsquo;s future direction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melody found an excellent wiki site produced by upstream about their plans for improvements to the GNU Image Manipulation Program&amp;rsquo;s UI: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gui.gimp.org/index.php?title=GIMP_GUI_Redesign&#34;&gt;https://gui.gimp.org/index.php?title=GIMP_GUI_Redesign&lt;/a&gt;. She is currently assessing how much of this could still be useful for us as much of the information has not been updated for quite some time. She also suggested we provide a wiki or image dump mechanism so examples and user studies could be stored in a useful location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potential future monetization options were also discussed. That open discussion will be picked up again later because the feedback we received is that we need to make sure any choices we make on this sensitive topic are practical, effective and not user-hostile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also discussion about a potential new save file format. We learned that OpenRaster is intended as more of an archive format than one likely to be used on a day-to-day basis, and that XCF is exensible. That opens up the possibility of storing undo steps and other file-specific functionality in future releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also general support for &amp;ldquo;non-destructive changes&amp;rdquo; and discussion of how that might be achieved. We understand this is being actively developed as part of the GEGL library, so could wait for those changes instead of implementing them ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss agreed with sponsor contributors&amp;rsquo; submitted issues after &amp;ldquo;dogfooding&amp;rdquo; the pre-release version of Glimpse that we should update patterns, brushes and templates if we can for 1.0 as these are long-standing problems whose fixes could have a big user impact. It may get pushed out if this turns out to be hard to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new issue was raised by the community about producing multiple output formats from the same save file instead of relying on users not saving destructive changes. It can be tracked here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/61&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/issues/61&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;website-updates&#34;&gt;Website Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss plans to move this Hugo site to the project&amp;rsquo;s build server once it has been provisioned to keep costs low. He expects this to happen within the next two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaomodus also provisioned a new MediaWiki instance for our project to use. It is available via &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.getglimpse.app&#34;&gt;https://wiki.getglimpse.app&lt;/a&gt; and over time we will populate this with helpful project information, user guides and design work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-plans-after-glimpse-10&#34;&gt;Future Plans After Glimpse 1.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a lot of discussion this week about the practical questions we may need to answer as part of a full code rewrite. In theory it is possible because most of the core functionality is now contained within the GEGL and BABL libraries. GNU Image Manipulation Program 2.10 primarily forms the graphical user interface, plug-in framework, help pages and other supplementary functionality so the learning curve is much shallower than we expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rewrite would be beneficial because we can spend time designing a new GUI with feedback from end users, eliminate decades of unneeded code and would have full freedom over the tools and technologies we want to use. However, such an undertaking would require a considerable amount of time, people and resources to produce. The most practical route seems to be to develop our own new codebase and improve the existing one at the same time in two &amp;ldquo;streams&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.x will be the &amp;ldquo;stream&amp;rdquo; that iterates new features and improvements on top of the existing GNU Image Manipulation Program 2.10.12 codebase. Helpful upstream changes would be incorporated periodically, and this would be the supported codebase for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.x will be the &amp;ldquo;stream&amp;rdquo; that is written entirely by our project. This would be slowly developed over a number of years, may produce cool changes that are subsequently backported to 1.x, and would be what we eventually switch to once it is fully ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course this could all be &amp;ldquo;pie in the sky&amp;rdquo; thinking as this project has only existed for a month so far! However, we think some long term planning about the future direction of the Glimpse project will help us focus our discussions and better assess the long term ramifications of our current decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates for Week Three</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/updates-for-week-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 01:51:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/updates-for-week-three/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;irc-channel-deprecated&#34;&gt;IRC Channel Deprecated&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stated last week that we would be deprecating the #glimpse IRC channel soon. After discussing that with the community we believe the switch to Matrix is now complete, so we can safely proceed with deprecating that communication method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To confirm: we no longer track, administer, support or own the #glimpse channel on Freenode&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you spot anyone abusing the IRC channel we have vacated, please report the incident to Freenode&amp;rsquo;s own staff moderators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To join the project discussion, please join us &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.to/#/#glimpse:matrix.org&#34;&gt;on Matrix&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know some people will find our decision on this disappointing, but this was a choice our community made. The feedback so far has been positive, and our contributors appreciate the lower barrier to entry and more modern client applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-changes&#34;&gt;Code Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been quite a few code changes made on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/tree/gimp2-10&#34;&gt;the gimp2-10 branch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clipsey removed redundant doc files and performed some code cleanup for us. She also continued work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/glir&#34;&gt;Glir&lt;/a&gt;, an automated tool intended to make the refactoring work in a future &amp;ldquo;hard fork&amp;rdquo; easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby Moss (or &amp;ldquo;trechnex&amp;rdquo;) removed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/about/ancient_history.html#publicity&#34;&gt;Wilber&lt;/a&gt; from the top of menus and its giant eyes from the main window. He also started updating the translation files to use the correct project name and made minor tweaks like fixing &amp;ldquo;tip of the day&amp;rdquo; and ensuring we display the correct Glimpse release version in the &amp;ldquo;about&amp;rdquo; window. He also added our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;Patreon sponsor contributors&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;code&gt;authors.xml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also switched to using the &amp;ldquo;system&amp;rdquo; UI theme by default with &amp;ldquo;legacy&amp;rdquo; icons from GNU Image Manipulation Program 2.8 for the time being. The other stock themes from upstream have been removed because we intend to replace them with more visually appealing and accessible alternatives. Chaomodus has already started producing some of those replacements for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-decisions&#34;&gt;Community Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community discussed how we should package the GNU/Linux port of Glimpse. It was agreed that &lt;a href=&#34;https://flatpak.org/&#34;&gt;Flatpak&lt;/a&gt; would be the preferred distribution mechanism and an &lt;a href=&#34;https://appimage.org/&#34;&gt;AppImage&lt;/a&gt; provided as an alternative for those who are unable to use Flatpaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A source tarball will also be provided for advanced users and distribution package maintainers for Linux, BSD and Solaris distributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also continued to discuss the project&amp;rsquo;s logo and there were a number of ideas and concepts posted to the Matrix channel. The most popular idea seemed to be a paintbrush splodging paint onto a Polaroid-style photo. Chris (or &amp;ldquo;Brainblasted&amp;rdquo;) has fed back to a fellow GNOME contributor that we would like to have the branding assets some time in August so we can aim for a 1.0 release before the end of that month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;website-updates&#34;&gt;Website Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have rearranged the About page and added new questions for &lt;a href=&#34;../../about/#how-do-i-stay-up-to-date-with-this-project&#34;&gt;how to follow news about Glimpse&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;../../about/#how-do-i-contribute-to-this-project&#34;&gt;how to get involved with this project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also now a provisional answer that lists &lt;a href=&#34;../../about/#which-operating-systems-do-you-support&#34;&gt;the operating systems we plan to support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Successful Second Week</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/a-successful-second-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 18:02:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/a-successful-second-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past week we have made a number of important code changes in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/tree/gimp2-10&#34;&gt;the gimp2-10 branch&lt;/a&gt;, such as making sure the core maintainers and our Patreon contributors are listed correctly within the source code and that the About/Help menu reflects the correct project information. A new &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/tree/cleanup&#34;&gt;cleanup branch&lt;/a&gt; was also setup so we can start to remove larger assets we don&amp;rsquo;t need from version control entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community has also shifted across to using our Matrix channels as their primary source of communication, and we added new channels like &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.to/#/#glimpse-github:matrix.org&#34;&gt;#glimpse-github:matrix.org&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.to/#/#glimpse-offtopic:matrix.org&#34;&gt;#glimpse-offtopic:matrix.org&lt;/a&gt;. We are continuing to track the &lt;strong&gt;#glimpse&lt;/strong&gt; freenode channel, but expect to deprecate it soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also further discussion on potential animal mascots and pitches for future UI changes that will be pursued once the first &amp;ldquo;soft fork&amp;rdquo; release has been made available. &lt;a href=&#34;https://radical.town/@chaomodus&#34;&gt;Chaomodus&lt;/a&gt; provided great ideas for splash screens, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://bobadon.co.uk/web/accounts/825&#34;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; has reached out to GNOME artwork contributors as part of our logo development efforts. Our eventual plan is to let the community decide which artwork ideas we should pursue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bobadon.co.uk/@bob&#34;&gt;Bobby Moss&lt;/a&gt; also produced new &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/glimpse-helper-scripts&#34;&gt;helper scripts&lt;/a&gt; to assist newcomers to the project so they can more easily install prerequisites and build the project source code. We look forward to improving this as we receive feedback from our community and the project itself develops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you again to everyone that has continued to spread the word about us on &lt;a href=&#34;https://bobadon.co.uk/@glimpse&#34;&gt;the fediverse&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/glimpse_editor&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, send us funds on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt; and joined the discussion on &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.to/#/#glimpse:matrix.org&#34;&gt;#glimpse:matrix.org&lt;/a&gt;. Your contributions have been invaluable and they are helping us maintain the momentum we need to produce our first release.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hectic First Week</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/a-hectic-first-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 22:46:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/a-hectic-first-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have been overwhelmed by the contributions and show of support from the community in just the first week of this project, and we are all deeply grateful. You are all amazing, and we hope we can keep this momentum going and deliver a fork everyone can be proud of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week we agreed on a communications platform (Matrix and IRC), confirmed that we will be sticking with Github, agreed on a code of conduct and discussed how the project will be governed (i.e. no &amp;ldquo;benevolent dictators&amp;rdquo;).  We have also publicly thanked two &amp;ldquo;elite supporters&amp;rdquo; from Patreon on two new social media channels we just set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a project we also agreed that the first release should be a &amp;ldquo;soft fork&amp;rdquo; so we can get the re-brand into everyone&amp;rsquo;s hands within weeks rather than months, then we can start being more ambitious with a &amp;ldquo;hard fork&amp;rdquo; shortly after. The code changes for our first release are already being worked on and can be viewed here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/tree/gimp2-10&#34;&gt;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse/tree/gimp2-10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions are still ongoing about our logo, splash screen and any potential animal mascots. If you would like to get involved then please join us on our project communications channels. (The current website is a placeholder and will be made to look more attractive in coming weeks!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some handy links to get you started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FAQs from our community: &lt;a href=&#34;https://getglimpse.app/about/&#34;&gt;https://getglimpse.app/about/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code of Conduct: &lt;a href=&#34;https://getglimpse.app/code-of-conduct/&#34;&gt;https://getglimpse.app/code-of-conduct/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fediverse/Mastodon: &lt;a href=&#34;https://bobadon.co.uk/@glimpse&#34;&gt;https://bobadon.co.uk/@glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/glimpse_editor&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/glimpse_editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matrix community:  &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.to/#/+glimpse:matrix.org&#34;&gt;https://matrix.to/#/+glimpse:matrix.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patreon: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;https://www.patreon.com/glimpse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So It Begins</title>
      <link>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/so-it-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 12:36:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glimpse-editor.org/posts/so-it-begins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you missed the drama, the catalyst for this initiative was a feature request being closed down on the GNU Image Manipulation Program&amp;rsquo;s project site: &lt;em&gt;(link redacted to respect the GNOME moderators&amp;rsquo; decision to hide the thread)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of us disagree that the name of the software is suitable for all users, and after 13 years of the project refusing to budge on this have decided to fork!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially this fork will just re-brand the existing v2.10.12, but the intention is that in the future as interest grows we will also add new functionality that addresses common user complaints. There is considerable interest in the idea, so we hope to use that to create something great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think the GNU Image Manipulation Program is a brilliant piece of photo editing software, but a fork provides the opportunity to forge a different path and share our changes back upstream so the wider community benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think this is a worthy pursuit you can follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glimpse-editor/Glimpse&#34;&gt;our github project&lt;/a&gt;, chat to us &lt;a href=&#34;https://bobadon.co.uk/@glimpse&#34;&gt;on the fediverse&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/glimpse&#34;&gt;donate via our Patreon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
